# Ray Garner

ray@perfectcast.co.uk raygarner.co.uk

### Personal Profile

I chose to study Computer Science because I find the work of software engineers like John Carmack and Linus Torvalds highly inspiring and also because I find programming exercises my imagination in a unique way. Developing software gives me a similar sense of satisfaction as composing music does, a prolific hobby of mine. Along with composing music, I have enjoyed playing in a variety of musical ensembles for several years now. This experience gave me the opportunity to practice my teamwork skills and creativity to a great extent, which quickly became useful during the group work project in the first year of my degree studies.

### **Education and Qualifications**

### University of Nottingham

- 2020-Present Studying in 2nd year of Computer Science Bsc. Core modules include software engineering group project, operating systems & concurrency, algorithms & efficiency and I've opted for optional modules in advanced functional programming, C++ programming and AI methods.
- 2019-2020 Attained a 1st with 87% overall in year 1 of Computer Science Bsc. Core modules included programming & algorithms, maths for computer science, systems & architecture, databases & interfaces and fundamentals of AI.

#### Wigston Academy Trust

- 2017-2019 Achieved A, A, B in A-Level Computer Science, Music Technology and Music
- **2015-2017** Passed 11 GCSEs with grades A\*-B

#### RSL

• 2018 - Passed Grade 8 electric guitar with merit

# Software Tools Experience

| Software development | vim, gcc, gdb, ghc, vscode, Eclipse IDE, JUnit testing, MATLAB, Visual Studio, Chrome dev tools, git, make |
|----------------------|--|
| Multimedia           | Reaper, Cubase, Ardour, ffmpeg, Audacity, Avid Sibelius, Musescore, GIMP, Blender                          |
| Network tools        | ftp, ssh, Citrix Receiver, VMware Horizon, TeamViewer  |
| Design               | Google SketchUp, Circuit Wizard  |
| Languages            | C, ARM asm, Java, Haskell, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, VB.NET, shell script, HTML, CSS, $\LaTeX$ , Markdown    |
| Operating systems    | Arch Linux, Debian Linux, Windows 7 onwards, macOS Sierra onwards  |

# Software Development Projects

- 2019-Present Maintain shell scripts to automate the installation and configuration of Arch Linux to my preferences
- 2020 Created a shell script wrapper for mpv and ffmpeg to create a multi-track recording tool
- 2020 Programmed a chess engine in Haskell using an alpha-beta search with a university colleague and later developed a faster version of the program in C
- 2020 Set up a film database website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL for the coursework in the databases and interfaces module in year one of my degree. I now maintain raygarner.co.uk as a portfolio using skills I learned during that project
- 2020 Wrote JUnit tests to debug a faulty finance app in the first group work module of my degree and also used git for version control

- 2020 Utilised the Java GUI library "swing" and object oriented programming techniques to create a Minesweeper game as a university assignment
- 2019 Completed various assignment exercises to gain experience with C, ARM asm, Java and Haskell during the first year of my degree
- 2018-2019 Created a primitive chess engine using VB.NET for A-Level Computer Science coursework for the college chess club

# Work Experience

### 2017-2020 - Perfectcast Ltd

- Upgraded laptop hardware
- Performed corporate laptop imaging
- Installed a Cisco video conference system
- Set up a Blender renderfarm
- Carried out end-user and network IT support

### 2016-2019 - Wigston Academy Trust

- Played as the guitarist for the shows Joseph and his amazing Technicolour Dreamcoat, Little Shop of Horrors, Annie and School of Rock
- Recording technician for GCSE Music recitals

#### 2019 - The Little Theatre

• Played as the guitarist for their production of Cats

### Hobbies and Other Experience

#### Music

- 2020 Played as lead guitarist and co-producer in Leicester math-rock band "PE Department"
- 2019-2020 Performed as lead guitarist in the Wigston College Jazz Band
- 2015-2019 Performed as lead guitarist in Leicester alt-rock band "The Scrubs"
- 2014 Sung in the choir in "The Armed man: A mass for Peace" at the Royal Albert Hall
- 2014 Played guitar in Rhys Chatham's "A Secret Rose" Birmingham Town Hall performance

### Chess

- 2020-Present Member of the University of Nottingham Chess Society
- 2019-2020 Co-head of the Wigston College Chess Club

References available upon request